linkedin.com/in/ckcasil github.com/ccasil cesarkylecasil.me

#### **Summary**

Cesar Kyle Casil is a Computer Science major from the University of California, Santa Cruz. He is currently practicing full stack web development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, Node.js); he has experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. Since coming from both an accredited university and a coding bootcamp, he has not only acquired a unique set of skills, but has learned the importance of how they lead to success within the tech industry. His primary goal is to contribute his passion for programming towards a company's vision while expanding on his technical skills.

#### Education

### University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley, CA

Apr 2018

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development

• Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

**Technical** Skills

<u>L</u>anguages: JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift, Python, LATEX

Front-End: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Re-

quest/Response

 $\mathbf{MySQL}, \overline{\mathrm{SQLite}}, \mathbf{PostgreSQL}, \overline{\mathrm{MongoDB}}, \overline{\mathrm{Mongoose.js}}, \overline{\mathrm{Django}}$  $\underline{\mathbf{D}}$ atabase: ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask <u>F</u>rameworks and Libraries: <u>D</u>evelopment Tools: Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services

> Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures, Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Architecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model

(EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM)

View Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

Experience

**VeEX Inc.**, Web Development Engineer, Fremont, CA

Apr 2019–Present

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

Jan 2018–Jan 2019

- Built full-stack, modern, responsive web applications while providing quick feedback and sup-
- Lead a small team in collaboration with clients in order to create websites from the ground up

#### MissionU, Research Intern, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017–May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

### Garcon LLC, Android Developer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016–Dec 2016

- Translated UI mockups into a working, interactive Android application using Android Studio and Java during its early stages
- Designed and created a functional implementation of the mobile applications interface • Testing and quality assurance

## **Projects**

## Tips and Templates

Miscellaneous:

Ongoing

Notes on various topics based around Computer Science.

• Technologies Used: Markdown, Git

Cesar Kyle Casil Personal Portfolio.

Ongoing

Paused

• Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 4, Responsive Web Design (RWD), Font Awesome, Google Analytics, Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Alex the Party E-commerce website selling photo prints. Takes customer from store front to cart to checkout.

• Technologies Used: Angular, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3,

Bootstrap 4, Responsive Web Design (RWD), Amazon EC2, Multer

Portfolio for Academy of Art student to display her studies in Fashion Journalism.

Megumi Hiramoto

Sept 2018–Dec 2018

• Technologies Used: React, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Responsive Wed Design (RWD), GoDaddy

#### Love Changing the World, Inc. Public website for the non-profit organization Love Changing the World, Inc. Allows donations

Jun 2018-Oct 2018

through PayPal in exchange for apparel with LCTW branding. • Technologies Used: React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap 4, HTML5,

Supp Apr 2018–Ongoing Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift 5, Core Data, Auto Layout, Icons8

CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API

# Dojo Attendance Tracker

calculator, and a log of main lifts.

Mar 2018

iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift 4, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data, Auto Layout

# Baskin-Robbins Birthday 31

Feb 2018

Web application tailored to Baskin-Robbins fans. Allows the registered user to view and add all the available flavors to a list of favorites, and uses location to find the nearest Baskin-Robbins through the Google Maps API. • Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5,

CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 4, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)

### Positions & Affiliations

Leadership

Lambda Phi Epsilon, Webmaster/Academics/Fundraiser Chair University of California, Santa Cruz • Created and maintained chapter website.

Mar 2014-Jun 2016

- Kept in close contact with members to promote excellence in academics.
- Focused on raising money for activities and services.